Guide to the Division of Academic Affairs Records RG 6
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Series 1. Administration
  - Departmental Annual Reports
    - 2005 - 2006
      - Administration: Admissions Annual Report, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_20_x (Box 26, Folder 20)
      - Administration: Media Services Annual Report, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_21_x (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - Administration: Office of Grant Programs Annual Report, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_22_x (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - Administration: Office of Institutional Research and Assesment Annual Report, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_23_x (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Ancell School of Business: Annual Report, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_24_x (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Ancell School of Business: Business Administration Annual Report, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_25_x (Box 26, Folder 25)
      - Ancell School of Business: Faculty Reports, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_26_x (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - Ancell School of Business: Management & Information Secuirty Annual Report, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_27_x (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - Ancell School of Business: Management Department, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_28_x (Box 26, Folder 28)
      - Graduate Studies: Campus Safety - Women's Center, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_29_x (Box 26, Folder 29)
      - Graduate Studies: E & EP Meeting, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_30_x (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - Professional Studies: Annual Report, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_31_x (Box 26, Folder 31)
      - Professional Studies: Bassett's Professioanl Activety Report, 2005-2006; RG6.xx_10_32_x (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - 2006 - 2007
      - Ancell School of Business: JLA Stragetic Plan, 2006-2007; RG6.xx_10_33_x (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - 2007 - 2008
      - Administration: Community Report Card, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_34_x (Box 26, Folder 34)
      - Graduate Studies: Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_35_x (Box 26, Folder 35)
      - Graduate Studies: Attchments, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_36_x (Box 26, Folder 36)
      - Graduate Studies: Biological & Enviromental Sciences, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_37_x (Box 26, Folder 37)
      - Graduate Studies: Business, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_38_x (Box 26, Folder 38)
      - Graduate Studies: Community Counseling, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_39_x (Box 26, Folder 39)
      - Graduate Studies: Counseling, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_40_x (Box 26, Folder 40)
      - Graduate Studies: Education, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_41_x (Box 26, Folder 41)
      - Graduate Studies: Graduate Council, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_42_x (Box 26, Folder 42)
      - Graduate Studies: Health, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_43_x (Box 26, Folder 43)
      - Graduate Studies: History, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_44_x (Box 26, Folder 44)
      - Graduate Studies: Instructioanl Leadership, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_45_x (Box 26, Folder 45)
      - Graduate Studies: Justice & Law Administration, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_46_x (Box 26, Folder 46)
      - Graduate Studies: Math, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_47_x (Box 26, Folder 47)
      - Graduate Studies: MFA, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_48_x (Box 26, Folder 48)
      - Graduate Studies: Music, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_49_x (Box 26, Folder 49)
      - Graduate Studies: NEASC, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_50_x (Box 26, Folder 50)
      - Graduate Studies: Nursing, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_51_x (Box 26, Folder 51)
      - Graduate Studies: Organizational Effecticeness w/Charter Oak & WCSU, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_52_x (Box 26, Folder 52)
      - Graduate Studies: Paint & Illustration, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_53_x (Box 26, Folder 53)
      - Graduate Studies: PAM, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_54_x (Box 26, Folder 54)
      - Graduate Studies: Professional Writing, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_55_x (Box 26, Folder 55)
      - Graduate Studies: Social Work & Human Services w/ WCSU & NCC, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_56_x (Box 26, Folder 56)
      - Graduate Studies: Stragetic Planning, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_57_x (Box 26, Folder 57)
      - Graduate Studies: Vision Committee, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_58_x (Box 26, Folder 58)
      - Graduate Studies: WestConn at Waterbury, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_59_x (Box 26, Folder 59)
      - Graduate Studies: WestConn Institue for Science Teacher Research, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_60_x (Box 26, Folder 60)
      - School of Arts & Science: Biology Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_62_x (Box 26, Folder 62)
      - School of Arts & Science: Chemistry Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_63_x (Box 26, Folder 63)
      - School of Arts & Science: Commuincations Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_64_x (Box 26, Folder 64)
      - School of Arts & Science: Computer Science Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_65_x (Box 26, Folder 65)
      - School of Arts & Science: English Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_66_x (Box 26, Folder 66)
      - School of Arts & Science: History Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_67_x (Box 26, Folder 67)
      - School of Arts & Science: Honors Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_68_x (Box 26, Folder 68)
      - School of Arts & Science: Mathematics Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_69_x (Box 26, Folder 69)
      - School of Arts & Science: PAM Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_70_x (Box 26, Folder 70)
      - School of Arts & Science: Philosophy Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_71_x (Box 26, Folder 71)
      - School of Arts & Science: Proposals, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_72_x (Box 26, Folder 72)
      - School of Arts & Science: Psychology Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_73_x (Box 26, Folder 73)
      - School of Arts & Science: Social Science Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_74_x (Box 26, Folder 74)
      - School of Arts & Science: World Languages, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_75_x (Box 26, Folder 75)
      - School of Arts & Science: Writing Annual Report, 2007-2008; RG6.xx_10_76_x (Box 26, Folder 76)
      - School of Arts & Sciences, 2007-2008 (Box 26, Folder 78)
        Two CDs
    - 2008 - 2009
      - Graduate Studies: Scholarships, 2008-2009; RG6.xx_10_77_x (Box 26, Folder 77)
  - Faculty - evaluations and rosters
    - Eastern States Association of Professional Schools for Teachers
      - Board of Control, 1958-1960 (Box 18, Folder 61)
      - Bulletins, 1954-1958 (Box 18, Folder 62)
      - Conferences, 1950-1960 (Box 18, Folder 63)
      - Little Eastern States Regional Conference, 1950-1959 (Box 18, Folder 64)
      - Regional Conference, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 65)
    - General
      - Evaluation of the Faculty of Students of WCSC, fall 1969/spring 1970 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
      - Faculty Data for fall 1972 (Box 19, Folder 3-7)
      - Faculty in Focus, 1980-1988 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Faculty Roster, 1972-1989 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Faculty Roster, 1990-2001 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Faculty Roster, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Faculty Workshops, 1952-1959 (Box 19, Folder 12-14)
      - New Faculty Directory, 1963-2001 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Quinnell, Bill, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Arts and Sciences, School of
    - Administrative
      - Dr. Braun's Study (partial), 1956 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Honors/Scholars Program, 1984-2000 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Six College Study, 1954-1955 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Undergraduate Studies/Administrative
      - Freshman Instructional Team Minutes, 1952-1955 (Box 17, Folder 26-27)
      - Interim Committee Reports, 1950-1956 (Box 17, Folder 28-29)
      - Interim Program Summary Report, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Interim Program Summary Report (c.2), 1953 (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Social Science/History Departmental Handbook [1969?], undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - Sophomore Instructional Team, 1952-1955 (Box 17, Folder 33-34)
      - Sophomore Boston Trip, Faculty Evaluation, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Undergraduate Studies/Art
      - Art Education, 1933-1934 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - Undergraduate Studies/German
      - German Studies, 1988-1999 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - Undergraduate Studies/History
      - History Department, 1973-1994 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - Undergraduate Studies/Interim Program, 1949-1958
      - Agencies of the Community, Form 3A, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 39-41)
      - Business, Industry of the Community, Form 3A, 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 42)
      - Elementary Education, Freshmen A-L, Forms 1 & 2, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 43)
      - Elementary Education, Freshmen, Form 3, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 44)
      - Elementary Education, Sophomores, Form 3, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 45-47)
      - Elementary Education, Sophomores, Parts 1 & 2, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 48-49)
      - Forms, 1949-1954 (Box 17, Folder 50)
      - General Education, Forms 1 & 2, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 51)
      - General Education, Form 3, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 52)
      - Lab. Tech., Nursing, Irreg. Form 3, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Music Education, Forms 1 & 2, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Music Education, Form 3, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Opinion Surveys, 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Other Significant Experiences, Form 3A, 1955-1956 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Parts A.B.C., Freshmen Class, 1955-1956 (Box 18, Folder 6-8)
      - Science, Forms 1 & 2, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Student Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Student Summary of Project, Form 3 & 4, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
      - Misc. Pamphlets, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Monuments of Culture, Humanities Syllabus, fall 1958 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Undergraduate Studies
      - Monuments of Culture, Humanities Syllabus, fall 1958 (c.2) (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Monuments of Culture, Humanities Syllabus, spring 1959, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Monuments of Culture, Humanities Syllabus, spring 1959 (c.2), 1958 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Music: Concert Choir & Wind Ensemble, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Music Department, A Short History by Russell Hirshfeld, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 18a)
      - Pamphlets and flyers, 2000-2003 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Revision of WCSU General Physics Laboratory Part II, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Social Sciences, Administrative, 1993-1995 (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Standard Practices in Writing and Speech, September 1936 (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Student Manual, A Report to the Faculty from the English Dept., undated (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Summer Daze, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 24)
      - Summer Session News, 1943-1964 (Box 18, Folder 25)
      - Women's Studies Program, 1990-2003 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Ancell School of Business
    - Academic Advisement Manual, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Ancell, Vol. 3, Issue 1, spring 1999 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Annual Report, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - JLA RAG, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - MSJA, 1995-2001 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
    - MSA and MBA Chronology, 1973-1977 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - MSA Course Outlines, 1976-1985 (Box 17, Folder 10-20)
    - Pamphlets, undated (Box 17, Folder 21-22)
  - School of Professional Studies
    - Departments
      - The Past and Present History of School of Professional Studies and Its Departments, September 2002 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Education, Department of
      - Annual Report, Office of Coordination, 1956-1958 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Connecticut Elementary School Principals Conference, May 9-10, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Connecticut School Document No. 1, Questions used at state teachers' examinations, 1919 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Course Outlines: Education Course Outlines (ca. 1959-1979), undated (Box 19, Folder 21-23)
      - Course Outlines: Elementary Education, Sixth Year Program, 1968-1972 (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - Course Outlines: Guidance and Counseling, 1970-1984 (Box 19, Folder 25-27)
      - Course Outlines: Music, 1973-1978 (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - Course Outlines: Physical Education, 1972-1974 (Box 19, Folder 29)
      - Course Outlines: Physics, 1974-1976 (Box 19, Folder 30)
      - Course Outlines: School Psychology, 1976-1978 (Box 19, Folder 31-33)
      - Course Outlines: Sixth Year Program in the Teaching of Reading, Proposal 1968-69, 1968-1996 (Box 19, Folder 34)
      - Curriculum, Four-Year Elementary (ca early 1930s), undated (Box 19, Folder 35)
      - Curriculum Committee Reports, 1972-1979 (Box 19, Folder 36)
      - Elementary School Service Bulletin (ca 1940s), undated (Box 19, Folder 37)
      - Elementary School Health Instruction Conference, Nov. 20, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 38)
      - Elementary Science, State Normal School, Danbury, Connecticut, 1914 (Box 19, Folder 39)
      - Final Report of the Presidents' Committee On Laboratory School Experiences, February 17, 1955. (Box 19, Folder 40)
      - Experiences, February 17, 1955. (c.2) (Box 19, Folder 41)
      - Laboratory Schools, Curriculum Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 19, Folder 42)
      - Laboratory Schools, Sophomore Participation, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 43)
      - Miscellaneous, 1919-1959 (Box 19, Folder 44)
      - The Nature of Man Program, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 45)
      - Pamphlets, undated (Box 19, Folder 46)
      - Practice Schools, Sketches From American Life, undated (Box 19, Folder 47)
      - Practice Teaching Report Forms (blank), undated (Box 19, Folder 48)
      - Pre-Service Teacher Education Study (Spring Progress Report), 6/15/55, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 49)
      - Professional Sub-Committee Reports, 1957-1978 (Box 19, Folder 50)
      - Report of Guidance Committee on Screening, April 1954 (Box 19, Folder 51)
      - Student Teaching, undated (Box 19, Folder 52)
      - Student Teaching/Liability, 1949-1950 (Box 19, Folder 53)
      - Teacher's Training Questionnaire (ca 6/9/43), undated (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - Health Promotion and Exercise Sciences Department
      - Pamphlets, 1998-2003 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Nursing, Department
      - Nursing, Department of, 1983-1986 (Box 19, Folder 55-57)
      - Health Education Pamphlets: American Red Cross, 1945-1947 (Box 19, Folder 58)
        "Love Is Not Enough"
        "Plan for a Happy Healthy Future; Prepare for it….NOW"
        "What Is….." The Red Cross Home Nursing Course Gives the Answers"
      - Health Education Pamphlets: Connecticut Cancer Society, 1945-1947 (Box 19, Folder 58)
        "Cancer, A Challenge to Youth"
        "Cancer of the Digestive Tract"
        "Changing of the Guard"
        "Fight Cancer"
        "Guard Those You Love"
        "Highlights in Cancer Control"
        "How your doctor detects cancer"
        "Positively Speaking….Cancer Can Be Beaten"
        "There Is Something YOU Can Do About Cancer
        "Who, What, Why, Where, When of Cancer"
        "Youth Looks at Cancer"
      - Health Education Pamphlets: Connecticut Dairy and Food Council, 1945-1947 (Box 20, Folder 1)
        "A Guide to Good Eating"
        "Baby Care Digest"
        "Check Your Lunch Today"
        "Food and Care for Good Dental Health"
        "Food for Young Children"
        "Food Value of Ice Cream"
        "Health and Nutrition in Family Living"
        "How Teeth Grow"
        "How to Help Your Children"
        "Milk…Let's Find Out About It"
      - Health Education Pamphlets: Connecticut Dairy and Food Council, 1945-1947 (Box 20, Folder 2)
        "My Friend the Cow"
        "My Reflections"
        "Nutrition News" April, December, 1946
        "Out of the Postman's Bag"
        "Safe Milk"
        "Straight from the Shoulder"
        "Ventures-Voyages-Vitamins"
      - Health Education Pamphlets: Connecticut Department of Health, 1945-1947 (Box 20, Folder 3)
        "Avoid Influenza"
        "Care of the Ear
        "The Child's Ears"
        "Common Colds"
        "Crippler In Disguise"
        "Dental Care Program, Social Service Information"
        "Diseases Spread from Mouth and Nose"
        "Eat a Good Breakfast"
        "Eat the Right Food to Help Keep You Fit"
        "Food for Growth"
        "Foods that Help to Build Sound Teeth"
        "Fluorine and Tooth Decay"
        "Gonorrhea, Its Cause, Spread, Cure"
        "Health Education Materials": Adults
        "Health Education Materials": Home Economics Classes
        "Health Education Materials": Intermediate Grades
        "Health Education Materials": Loan Catalog
        "Health Education Materials": Primary Grades
        "Health Education Materials": Upper Grades, Junior and Senior High Schools
        "Heart Disease and its Prevention"
        "How to Save a Life From Drowning"
        "How to Save Teeth-and Money"
        "Immunization Prevents Smallpox, Diphtheria, Whooping Cough, Scarlet Fever, Tetanus, Typhoid. Be Wise! Immunize!"
      - Health Education Pamphlets: Connecticut Department of Health, 1945-1947 (Box 20, Folder 4)
        "Is Your Community In Balance for Health Protection"
        "Know Your Food Vitamins"
        "Malaria, Lessons On Its Cause and Prevention for Use in Schools"
        "Meet Your Public Health Nurse"
        "National Good Guide"
        "Nutrition, A Handbook"
        "Occupational Therapy, A Pioneering Profession"
        "Order Blank for Health Leaflets"
        "Poliomyelitis (Infantile Paralysis)"
        "Posture"
        "Posture Exercises"
        "A Primer On Infantile Paralysis, The Disease and Its Treatment"
        "Problems in the Prevention and Relief of Diseases of the Heart"
      - Health Education Pamphlets: Connecticut Department of Health, 1945-1947 (Box 20, Folder 5)
        "The Public Health Nurse and You"
        "Public Health Nursing Program and Functions"
        "Solid Facts for "Teen-Age" Folks"
        "State Services for Crippled Children"
        "Syphilis, Its Cause, Spread, Cure"
        "Teachers Should Report Diseases"
        "That They Too May Share a Brighter Tomorrow"
        "The Toothbrush"
        "Tuberculosis Can Be Prevented"
        "Wedding Plans, Venereal Disease Tests"
        "What Your Health Department Does to Protect Your Health"
        "What's Nu in Nutrition?"
      - Pamphlets, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - A Report to the Commission on Collegiate Nursing Education, 2008 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Social Work
      - Social Work, Department of, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Field Practicum Manual, Revised June 1999 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Division of Graduate Studies and External Programs
    - General
      - Applications/Pamphlets, undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
      - Courses Abroad, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 28-30)
      - External Programs (Waterbury), 2000-, 2000-2008 (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - First Graduate Committee and Degree Awarded, 1955-1957 (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - Western after 5, 1985-1986 (Box 18, Folder 32A)
    - Graduate Studies, Course Outlines
      - Master of Arts Degree Program, 1973-1978 (Box 18, Folder 33-34)
      - Master of Fine Arts (MFA), 1998 (Box 18, Folder 35)
      - Master of Audio-Visual Communications, 1969-1971 (Box 18, Folder 36)
      - Master of Arts in Economics, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 37)
      - Master of Arts in English, 1969-1979 (Box 18, Folder 38-40)
      - Master of Arts in French and Spanish Linguistics, undated (Box 18, Folder 41)
      - Master of Arts in Health Education, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 42)
      - Master of Arts in History, 1971-1983 (Box 18, Folder 43-45)
      - Master of Arts in Mathematics, Applied & Theoretical, 1969-1979 (Box 18, Folder 46-48)
      - Master of Oceanography and Limnology, 1973-1984 (Box 18, Folder 49-51)
      - Master of Arts in Social Sciences, 1971-1986 (Box 18, Folder 52-57)
      - Master of Arts in Psychology, 1974-1976 (Box 18, Folder 58-60)
- Series 2. Accreditation
  - Academic Planning Steering Committee
    - Self Assessment, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 22-25)
    - Self Assessment (c.2), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 26-30)
    - Department and School Self-Assessment Reports, April 15, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Academic Planning Committee Report, August 1998, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Departmental Responses to Academic Planning Steering Committee Report, October 9, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
    - Departmental Reponses: Addendum to Academic Planning Steering Committee Report, October 27, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Response to Academic Planning Committee Report, Health Science Department, November 2, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - School of Arts and Sciences, Program/Option Self-Assessment, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 29-34)
    - HSC/PE Response to Academic Planning Committee Report, October 9, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 35-37)
    - UPBC Academic Planning Report, Academic Years 2001-04, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - American Association of Teachers Colleges (AATC)
    - Minimum Standards for Accrediting Teachers Colleges and Normal Schools, Rev. February 1947 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Recommended Standards Governing Professional Laboratory Experiences and Student Teaching, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Ancell School of Business
    - Accreditation Report, MSA, March 1979 (Box 1, Folder 39-42)
    - Accreditation Report, MSA, June 1980 (Box 1, Folder 43-45)
    - Accreditation Report, MSA Public and Non-Profit, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - AACSB Peer Review Team, Team Report, April 22, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - AACSB: Standards for Business and Accounting Accreditation, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - AACSB: Standards for Business and Accounting Accreditation, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Dean's Summary of the Ancell School of Business Self Assessment 1998 Association to Accredit College Teacher Education (AACTE) (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Revisitation Program, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Evaluation Schedule, Standard I, II, VI, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Evaluation Schedule, Standard III-VII, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 53-54)
    - Standard I Committee, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Standard II-IV, Evaluation Schedules, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Standard V, VI, IX (1953), undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Report to the AACTE, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 58-59)
    - Appendix to the Report, Documentary Evidence, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1-10)
    - Executive Committee Annual Report, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Education I, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Source Book on Accreditation of Teacher Education, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - MINFO MINIREPORT I, II, III, IV, undated, [1975] (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ancell Program Self-Assessment, Dec.2000 (Box 10, Folder 24-28)
  - Connecticut Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education (CCATE)
    - Information Prepared for the Accreditation of the Graduate Program, May 1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Connecticut State Department of Education (CSDE)
    - Report On Teacher Education Programs At Western Connecticut State College (ca 1970-1975), undated (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
    - Correspondence, Teacher Education Re-accreditation, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Teacher Education at Western Connecticut State University, A Report to the State Board of Education, March 1984 (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
    - Teacher Education at Western Connecticut State University, A Report to the State Board of Education, March 1984 (c.2) (Box 2, Folder 23-25)
    - Self Examination Report on Education. Preparation Programs at WCSU, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
  - Institutional Research and Assessment
    - Institutional Assessment Plan, Fall 1988-Spring 1995, Jan. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Biennial Assessment Report, June 1992 (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
    - Biennial Assessment Report, June 1994 (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
    - First Biennial Institutional Report, Pursuant to Public Act 93-201, Dec 1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Biennial Assessment Report, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - National Council for the Accreditation of Teacher Education (NCATE)
    - Reevaluation Report to the NCATE, November 4-6, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Reappraisal Report to the NCATE, October 1968 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Report to the NCATE, Basic and Advanced Programs, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 37-43)
    - Graduate Teacher Education at Western Connecticut State College, A Report Prepared for the NCATE, July 1976 (Box 2, Folder 44-45)